<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithms on Abu Baker Al-Shammari</title>
    <link>http://bikibuku.com/algorithm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algorithms on Abu Baker Al-Shammari</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 21:57:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bikibuku.com/algorithm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Elementary searching methods</title>
      <link>http://bikibuku.com/algorithm/searchmethod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 21:57:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bikibuku.com/algorithm/searchmethod/</guid>
      <description>Get the keys and sort them asap In these type of exercises you often get some keys, in the order left to right where space does not count. It is not hard, but I recommend to draw the tree and always keep some extra space in case you mess up. I will go through heap, binary search tree, 2-3-4 tree and red black tree.
The keys are: M A N C H E S T E R</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filecompression</title>
      <link>http://bikibuku.com/algorithm/filecompression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 16:22:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bikibuku.com/algorithm/filecompression/</guid>
      <description>Compression using the LZW algorithm The algorithm was created ~1984 and is a simple algorithm to implement. In these type of exercises they provide us information that we start with 256 index and up, and we have to write the output. Lets use &amp;ldquo;SASS_SASSER_SAM_SAMRE&amp;rdquo; as an example.
I recommend to write input, dictionary and output in a table.
The meaning of this algorithm is to re-use words in the dictionary so the output gets compressed, it is explained what is happening in the comment section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hashing</title>
      <link>http://bikibuku.com/algorithm/hashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 12:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bikibuku.com/algorithm/hashing/</guid>
      <description>Some basic information about hashing I would like to remind you that there are many different types of hashing, the one I am using is used in my course. The code is from Algorithms in C++ by Robert Segdewick.
In this type of hashing you will find array, keys and return value.  The integer M is the length of the array, in this case it is 17 (0-16). You got two different hash types, where k is the letter number (A = 1).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>